Guide to the Tillie Olsen Papers, 1930-1990 M0667
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 14: Accession 2009-220
  - Tillie's Writings: publications, fragments, notes, interviews
    - Miscellaneous fragments: re. Sylvia Plath (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous fragments: "Artistic Journey" (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous fragments: "Unevens" (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous fragments/notes, 1950s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Tillie's verse [photocopies, chronological] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "Unevens" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Tillie's verse [photocopies, chronological] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "Unevens" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1960s] (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1966, 1980s] (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1959, 1978] (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa early 1970s] (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1970 - 1980s] (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1974], Santa Cruz (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1977], Banff (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1978] (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1980s ?] (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1997/98] (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated [1950s - ?] (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, photocopies [1953-1955?] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1970s - early 1980s] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1987] (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1990s ?] (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1990s] (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1995 ?] (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated [photocopies] (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated [photocopies] - Banff (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [circa 1982-1985] (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [Requa?] (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Early Writings, letters, etc. [photocopies] (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated [Motherhood ?] (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated [photocopies] (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "thoughts on class" (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [Requa ?] (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [Requa ?] (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, [Requa ?] (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments and drafts, "The Education of the Oracle to Connie Smith" (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "Blake" (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "Writing During the Thirties" (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, "The First 60 Years," Newsweek article (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Yonnondio, makings (photocopies) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous fragments/correspondence [photocopies] (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous fragments [Richard McCann ?] (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous fragments [Silences ?] (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous fragments [Motherhood ?] (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fragments [Motherhood ?], feminism (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous lyrics/writings, [author unknown; possibly TLO] (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Song lyrics copied out by TLO, fragments (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/journals [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/journals [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Olsen notebooks: Ann Sexton's excerpts (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Olsen notebook: [ca. 1960] (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Olsen notebook: [ca. 1962] (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Olsen notebook: [ca. 1963] (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Olsen notebook: [ca. 1974] (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Olsen notebook: [ca. 2001] (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/notepads/address books, various dates (~ 12 items) (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/notepads/address books, various dates (~32 items) (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/notepads/address books, various dates (~31 items) (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks/notepads/address books, various dates (~57 items) (Box 31)
    - Squeaks (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "Tell Me a Riddle," corrections (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Requa I, photocopies with corrections (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Silences, photocopies (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Various forewords/afterwords by TLO (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Intro to "Mothers & Daughters" (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "The Word Made Flesh," 12th Annual H. W. Reninger lecture (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Statement of plans at Radcliffe Institute, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "The Strike," photocopy (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "Canyon Story," with corrections (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "Response to Responses," drafts (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Circle of Women Artists, "Chapter 10" drafts (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - "Sleepy," photocopy (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes re. proposal for Pioneering Anthology (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "Yonnondio," manuscript (photocopies) (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - National Conference on Motherhood, Ohio 1978 (transcript and edits) (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous publications (photocopies), with fragments (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "Night-time tape" (transcript) and misc. quotations (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Requa memorabilia (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "Any Woman after Miscarriage," Tillie Olsen (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 1930's play (fragment): author/title unknown [Tillie ?] (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified manuscript [Tillie ?] (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Tell Me a Riddle," performed at the Caravan Theater, Cambridge, Massachusetts (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "I Didn't Raise My Boy" (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified manuscripts (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Tillie Olsen publications (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Published Writings (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "The Strike" (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous articles by Tillie Olsen (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Various interviews (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "I Want You Women Up North to Know," including letter to New Masses (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Bibliographies (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Tillie Olsen interview, January 1975 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - "These Things Shall Be," Tillie Olsen interview, 2003 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Newsweek: "The 30's," including Tillie Olsen, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Reading Lists by Tillie Olsen (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Tillie Olsen Speeches (some incomplete) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous writings: concerning women, sexism (Card-box 43)
    - P.E.N. membership list (resource for "Silences"), 1971 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Misc. correspondence re. Requa contract, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Oversized xeroxes of small notebooks (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Book reviews/articles/papers regarding Tillie Olsen
    - Press releases re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Flyers/events re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Book reviews (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Speeches/Introductions about Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Dedications to Tillie Olsen (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - The Feminist Press, 2007 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Articles/Papers re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Articles/Papers re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Articles re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Articles re. Tillie Olsen (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Press releases, flyers regarding Tillie Olsen (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Up Fron Under," 1971 with "I Stand Here Ironing" (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Blue Collar Review," Winter 2006-2007; "Tillie Olsen: Storyteller of Working America," 1980 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Ms. magazine, 1974, 2007 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - The Progressive, November 1999 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Advertisements for Tillie Olsen's books (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Writings/Publications by others
    - "Prelude to Fascism," by Toby Mathew Edwards, May 1995 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "The Great Unexamined," Chapter 1, by Janet Zandy (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Influence of Environment Upon Human Industries or Arts," Otis Tufton Mason, 1895 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous writings (unknown authors) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Poem from Grace [?] to Tillie, signed (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "'I'm for It,' Friendship and Change with Tillie Olsen," by Sandy Boucher (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Directions," play adapted from "O Yes," by Bob Fles (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Letters from Asia," by Ericka Lutz and Bill Sonnenschen (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "The Gumby Letters," by Ericka Lutz (chapters 1-15) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "The Gumby Letters," by Ericka Lutz (chapters 16 - epilogue) (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Sober Love Poems," by Aya de Leon (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Readers RE-Unite: Volume 2 of Books that Changed Us" (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Louise Todd Lambert: oral history, transcript (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "I Want You to Understand," Emily Hulot Olson (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - "We are Built of Light," Jonah Bornstein (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - "Elegy" by Carolyn Froche (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Appearances, Honorariums, etc.
    - Tillie Appearances (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Tillie Olsen's Special Song Book (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Misc. Awards (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Honorary Degrees (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Misc. Tillie Olsen Memorial material (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - A Celebration of the Life of Tillie Lerner Olsen (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Tillie Olsen Day (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Peace to You" (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "In Memoriam," Frieda King (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Programs for events involving or about Tillie Olsen (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Tillie Olsen: A Heart in Action" (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Guestbook, 3/25/1989 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Guestbook, nd (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous plaques and awards (Carton 48)
  - Miscellaneous
    - "Under the Olive," 1880 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Warsaw Ghetto/Lenin's funeral (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous World War II compilation of stories (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Chekhov in the Crimea (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Blanche Ames Drawings, reproductions (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Blanche Ames political cartoons (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Agnes Smedley: Arizona State University exhibit photographs (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Eldridge Cleaver to Beverly Axelrod, 1965 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous reprints (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - "Background of English Literature," Central High School, Omaha, Nebraska (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - "How the Ancients Moved Heavy Masses," W. F. Durfee (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Historic Stamps of America (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Anne Sexton poetry, photocopies (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Betty de Losada's "Tillie" file (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Labor History Rediscovered, box 1 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Fund for Independent Publishing (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Ruth Robet's journal (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1944-1945 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Interview with Don Cryer (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Addresses (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - PTA scrapbook, 1948 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Tillie Olsen's items from hall bulletin board (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Tillie Olsen's items from hall bulletin board (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous posters/awards (Flat-box 45, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera/clippings (Flat-box 45, Folder 2)
    - "The Yank," March 2, 1945 (Flat-box 45, Folder 3)
    - World War II newspapers (Flat-box 45, Folder 4)
    - World War II newspapers (Flat-box 45, Folder 5)
    - World War II newspapers (Flat-box 45, Folder 6)
    - 1801/1848 newspapers (Doug Kline gift to Tillie Olsen) (Flat-box 45, Folder 7)
    - Tillie Olsen: 2004 listing of books/materials (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Stanford University Legal Contracts/Correspondence
    - Stanford University legal contracts (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Stanford University legal contracts (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Stanford University legal contracts (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Stanford University legal contracts (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Stanford University legal contracts (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 2001 correspondence with Bill McPheron (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Tillie Olsen: corrections to initial Stanford listing (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Tillie Olsen: corrections to initial Stanford listing (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - 2009 inventory (accession 2009-220), initial listing (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Medical Files: RESTRICTED
    - Tillies Medical Files (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Medical receipts (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Medical: regarding Lakeside, Alzheimer's, etc. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - The Tillie Olsen 1998 Living Trust (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Tillie Olsen: Power of Attorney (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Last Will and Testament of Tillie Olsen (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Tillie Olsen Memorial Fund (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Tillie Olsen Memorial Fund (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Daphne Fernwood Funeral (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Certificate of death (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Tax/Business/personal material: RESTRICTED
    - Legal documents (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - San Bernandino Contract, May/June 2002 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "C and I" retreat, May/June 2002 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Laurie Olsen personal contracts (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 1997 Consulting and Income (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Supportive documentation for 2001 taxes (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Contracts, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Taxes, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Contracts, 2002 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Tillie Olsen Trust, 2007 accounting (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Tillie Olsen: recommendations (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Tillie Olsen: recommendations (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Laurie Olsen: graduate school application (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Media, 1990-2005; 0.5 Linear feet 6 VHS tapes; 1 Umatic tape; 2 DVD's
    - "An Interview with Tillie Olsen," Bruce Schwartz (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 1)
    - "Tillie Olsen: The Courage to Put Forth Her Own Voice," National Museum of Women in the Arts (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 2)
    - "Tillie Olsen: The Courage to Put Forth Her Own Voice," copy 2 (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 3)
    - "Tillie Olsen: The Courage to Put Forth Her Own Voice," copy 3 (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 4)
    - "Tell Me A Riddle" (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 5)
    - Visiting Artists 1983 (VHS) (Box 46, Videotape 6)
    - Visiting Artists 1983 (UMATIC) (Box 46, Videotape 7)
    - Tillie Olsen, KQED radio, 1/3/06 (CD) (Box 46, Disk 1)
    - Tillie Olsen: Mother's Day, 2000 (CD) (Box 46, Disk 2)